Guide to the Ruth Stephan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ruth Stephan papers
1915-1974
YCAL MSS 423
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
60
(148 boxes)
The Ruth Stephan Papers consist of correspondence, writings, research files, audiovisual material, photographs, and diaries and other personal papers documenting the career and life of the twentieth-century American writer, editor, and translator Ruth Stephan. Correspondence and subject files provide evidence of Stephan's professional and personal relationships as well as her wide-ranging interests, from art to Zen Buddhism. Stephan's creative work consists of drafts, notes, and research files for poetry, historical and autobiographical fiction, anthologies, and film; her research files on Queen Christina of Sweden are extensive. Her travels in and creative work related to Europe, Peru, Japan, China, and India are documented throughout the collection by writings, diaries and engagement calendars, photographs, film, sound recordings, and correspondence. The papers also include a small amount of material documenting the history of the Walgreens drugstore chain.
Stephan, Ruth, 1910-1974
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and Bequest of Ruth Stephan Franklin, 1965-1975. Gift of John J. Stephan, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Correspondence and diaries in boxes 51 and 118-121 are restricted until January 1, 2024.
Audiovisual material in Series III, boxes 116, 117, and 140, is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Reference copies of audiovisual material in Series III may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Tiger's Eye Records, YCAL MSS 362.
Ruth Stephan (1910-1974)
The writer Ruth Stephan (born Charlotte Ruth Walgreen) published her first poems in the late 1930s in venues such as Harper's, Poetry, and Forum, and her first volume, Prelude to Poetry, was published in 1946. With her husband, the painter John Stephan, she founded and edited the influential quarterly magazine The Tiger's Eye (1947-1951), which showcased the work of artists and writers with particular emphasis on abstract expressionism. In addition to further volumes of poetry, her work includes two novels based on the life of Queen Christina of Sweden, The Flight (1956) and My Crown, My Love (1960); a volume of translated Quechua stories and songs, The Singing Mountaineers (1957); an audio compilation, The Spoken Anthology of American Literature (1963); and a documentary film, Zen in Ryoko-in (1971). Her philanthropic work included establishing a poetry center at the University of Arizona in 1960.
Stephan was born in Chicago on January 21, 1910, the daughter of drugstore founder Charles R. Walgreen and Myrtle Norton Walgreen. She attended Northwestern University but left without a degree in 1929 when she married Justin W. Dart, with whom she had two sons. Unsupported by her family when she began to take herself seriously as a writer, she divorced Dart in 1939. Later that same year she married the painter John Stephan; their only child, a son, was born in 1941. In 1942 the Stephans moved to Westport, Connecticut, where they founded The Tiger's Eye in 1947. This venture lasted until 1951, when the work of producing the magazine threatened to overtake the couple's own creative work. In 1961, Ruth Stephan divorced John Stephan and spent time traveling in Japan and Southeast Asia, where she became interested in Zen Buddhism. In 1966 she married John C. Franklin, a scientist, and lived the remainder of her life in Greenwich, Connecticut. She died in North Salem, New York, on April 9, 1974.
Much of the information in this biographical sketch is drawn from: Stephan, John J., "Ruth Stephan (1910-74): A Tribute" ( Yale University Library Gazette, April 1976).
Scope and Contents
The Ruth Stephan Papers consist of correspondence, writings, research files, audiovisual material, photographs, and diaries and other personal papers documenting the career and life of the twentieth-century American writer, editor, and translator Ruth Stephan. Correspondence and subject files provide evidence of Stephan's professional and personal relationships as well as her wide-ranging interests, from art to Zen Buddhism. Stephan's creative work consists of drafts, notes, and research files for poetry, historical and autobiographical fiction, anthologies, and film; her research files on Queen Christina of Sweden are extensive. Her travels in and creative work related to Europe, Peru, Japan, China, and India are documented throughout the collection by writings, diaries and engagement calendars, photographs, film, sound recordings, and correspondence. The papers also include a small amount of material documenting the history of the Walgreens drugstore chain.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1915-1974. Series II. Writings, 1936-1974. Series III. Audiovisual Material, undated. Series IV. Other Papers, 1928-1972.
Tiger's eye; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Art -- Periodicals; Editors -- United States; Quechua Indians; Translators; Zen Buddhism; China -- Description and travel; India -- Description and travel; Japan -- Description and travel; Peru -- Description and travel; Audiotapes; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Motion pictures (visual works); Christina, Queen of Sweden, 1626-1689; Franklin, John C., 1904-1989; Holmes, Phoebe Barton, 1884-1969; Kobori, Nanrei Sohaku, 1918-1998; ReQua, Eloise G., 1903-1989; Stephan, Frederick W. (Frederick Walter), 1873-1965; Stephan, John J. (John Jason), 1941-; Stephan, John Walter, 1906-1995; Stephan, Ruth, 1910-1974; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Walgreen, Charles R. (Charles Rudolph), 1873-1939; Walgreen, Chuck, 1906-2007; Walgreen, Myrtle R. Norton, 1879-1971; University of Arizona. Poetry Center; Walgreens (Firm)
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1915-1974; Series I; 20.64; (51 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: General Correspondence (alphabetical), Subject Files (alphabetical), and Family Correspondence (chronological). This organization reflects the order of the material as received by the library.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains three runs of mixed correspondence and subject files, which largely represent Stephan's own filekeeping. The first subseries, General Correspondence, consists of correspondence filed by name of individual or organization, but also includes files on subjects such as "Birds" and "Race Relations." The second subseries, Subject Files, consists of correspondence and other information filed by subject, with some unsorted correspondence at the end. The final subseries, Family Correspondence, consists of family letters and documents donated by Stephan's son in 2003. Stephan's correspondence with family members can be found in all three suberies.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Correspondence in Box 51 is restricted until January 1, 2024.
  - General Correspondence
    - "A" general, 1961-1972 (Box 1)
    - Abels, Cyrilly, 1963, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Akesson, Elof, 1961-1971 (Box 1)
    - Aldrich, Michael, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Alpha Phi, 1965-1973 (Box 1)
    - Amerasinghe, Hamilton Shirley, 1964 (Box 1)
    - American Friends Service Committee, Inc., 1969 September (Box 1)
    - Anderson, S. A., 1965-1972 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Eleanor, No year January 15 (Box 1)
    - Anselmi, Giuseppe, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
    - Auchincloss, Louis A., 1963, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Audubon Society, 1970, 1973 (Box 1)
    - The Authors Guild, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    - "B" general, 1961-1973; 4 (Box 1)
    - Bagri: Mani, Savitri, and Indira, 1964-1971 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Julia, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - Barber, Melanie, 1964-1973 (Box 1)
    - Barnett, Anna F., 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Barnhill, Mattie, 1960-1973; 2 (Box 2)
    - Barton, Esther M., 1968-1971 (Box 2)
    - Baro, Gene, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
    - Basso, Hamilton, 1961-1967 (Box 2)
    - Basu, Utpal K., 1963-1966 (Box 2)
    - Bayanawala, Birju, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - Beck, Julian, 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    - Behn, Harry, 1969, 1973, undated (Box 2)
    - Benton, William, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - Beny, Roloff, 1962-1968 (Box 2)
    - Bergroth, Kersti, 1956-1967; 2 (Box 2)
    - Bevan, Bryan, 1959-1963 (Box 2)
    - Binkerd, Joan and Alfred, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Birds - correspondence and information, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Blume, Ebie and Peter, 1965-1973 (Box 2)
    - Bock, Frederick, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - Bokum, Fanny Butcher, 1960-1973 (Box 2)
    - Bontempo, Oreste and Victoria, 1964-1972 (Box 3)
    - Bourgeois, Louise, 1966-1973 (Box 3)
    - Bowen, Croswell, 1965-1968 (Box 3)
    - Bowyer, Sanford J., 1968, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Branker, Gloria, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
    - Brendel, Therese, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Brennand, Mollie, 1969-1972 (Box 3)
    - Brooks, Ginnie and Gerry, undated (Box 3)
    - Brooks, Gladys, 1966-1969, undated (Box 3)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1953-1965 (Box 3)
    - Brooks, Vickie, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - Brown, Nils F., undated (Box 3)
    - Bruce, Evangeline and David, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
    - Burrows, Helen, 1964-1971 (Box 3)
    - Buultjens: Bobson, Ernie, Paul, and Diana, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Buultjens, Ralph, 1962-1973; 2 (Box 3)
    - Bute, Mary Ellen, 1965-1972 (Box 3)
    - Buxton, Claudia and Tony, 1963-1965 (Box 3)
    - "C" general, 1951-1973; 3 (Box 4)
    - Cadel, John N., 1961-1970 (Box 4)
    - Cairncross, A. S., 1962-1967 (Box 4)
    - Carr, James F., 1966, December 9 (Box 4)
    - Cervantes, Marcelo, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1965-1970; 2 (Box 4)
    - Charlton, Maryette (continued), 1965-1970; 2 (Box 5)
    - Chicago Historical Society, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Clark, L. D. and LaVerne, 1964-1971 (Box 5)
    - Clarke, Mary Kay, 1968-1973 (Box 5)
    - Colby, Rachel and John, 1967, 1969 (Box 5)
    - College of Librarianship Wales, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Common Cause, 1973 January 24 (Box 5)
    - Conover, Richard and Betty, 1962-1972 (Box 5)
    - Copley, Alfred L., 1964-1966 (Box 6)
    - Corea, Gamini, 1962-1966 (Box 6)
    - Croce, Elena, 1959-1964 (Box 6)
    - Crostarosa, Noemi, 1965-1972 (Box 6)
    - Crowe, Philip K., 1961-1970 (Box 6)
    - Cuchiara, James, 1963-1969 (Box 6)
    - Cyrus, Bindley, 1970 May 1 (Box 6)
    - "D" general, 1951-1973 (Box 6)
    - Dart, Fusako, 1961-1974; 2 (Box 6)
    - Dart, Justin, 1965-1972; 3 (Box 7)
    - Dart, Justin Whitlock, 1964-1972 (Box 7)
    - Dart, Peter, 1964-1972; 2 (Box 7)
    - Dart, Suzanne, 1963-1973; 3 (Box 7)
    - Davidson, Jennie, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
    - Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), 1962-1972 (Box 7)
    - De Merivale, Lissy, 1963-1966 (Box 8)
    - De Vries, Peter, 1961-1965 (Box 8)
    - DeChabert, Ansetta, undated (Box 8)
    - Dennis, Imogene, 1957-1971; 2 (Box 8)
    - Deraniyagala, P. E. P. (Paulus Edward Pieris) and Siren, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
    - Desai, C. C., 1963-1970 (Box 8)
    - Diamond, Hester and Harold, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - Dock, Maia and Bill, 1972-1973, undated (Box 8)
    - Dodson, Owen, 1963-1973 (Box 8)
    - Dlugoszewski, Lucia, [1972] (Box 8)
    - "E" general, 1963-1972 (Box 8)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1961 May (Box 8)
    - Edwards, Harold W., 1957-1971 (Box 8)
    - Eggericky, Dorothy Parramore, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
    - Employees
      - General correspondence, 1942-1960; 3 (Box 8)
      - General correspondence (continued), 1942-1960; 2 (Box 9)
      - Alton, Lempi and Gustav, 1962-1965 (Box 9)
      - Armbruster, Silvia, 1970 (Box 9)
      - Eberlein, Roxane, 1968-1970 (Box 9)
      - Giannetto, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 9)
      - Mazurak, Evelyn, 1958-1961; 2 (Box 9)
      - Neal, Eleva, 1960-1964 (Box 9)
      - Yule, Dorothy, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1956-1973 (Box 9)
    - Ewald, William Bragg, 1968-1972 (Box 9)
    - "F" general, 1957-1973; 3 (Box 10)
    - Fabion, John, 1966, undated (Box 10)
    - Faruffini, Marco Giulio, 1957-1967 (Box 10)
    - Felding, Catherine and Howard, 1966, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Field, Henry, 1965-1969 (Box 10)
    - Fisher, Henry Johnson, 1961-1965 (Box 10)
    - Fitzpatrick, Francis, 1969-1973 (Box 10)
    - Flaherty, Frances, 1966, undated (Box 10)
    - Fonseka, Dora, 1963-1970 (Box 10)
    - Franklin, John C., 1971-1974; 2 (Box 10)
    - Franklin, John C. (continued), 1971-1974; 2 (Box 11)
    - Franklin, Peter, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - Fredericks, Claude, 1963-1966 (Box 11)
    - Freedom Schools, 1964-1966 (Box 11)
    - Freeman, Joe and Charmion von Wiegand, 1963-1971 (Box 11)
    - Friends of the Folger Library, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Friends of Literature, 1965-1972 (Box 11)
    - Fuerbringer, Otto and Winnie, 1965, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Futehally, Zeenuth, 1966-1973 (Box 11)
    - "G" general, 1961-1973; 2 (Box 11)
    - Gallup, Donald Clifford, 1970 August 12 (Box 12)
    - Garden Club of Illinois, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
    - Gladwin, Helen and Ellis, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
    - Goldschmidt, Lucien, 1968 November 9 (Box 12)
    - Gotham Book Mart, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - Greenwich Library, 1956-1973 (Box 12)
    - Gregor, Arthur, 1967-1970 (Box 12)
    - Gunasinghe, Siri, 1962-1971 (Box 12)
    - Gupta, Pradip, 1965-1972 (Box 12)
    - "H" general, 1947-1973; 2 (Box 12)
    - Hambro, Elisabeth and Eddie, 1962-1973 (Box 12)
    - Hammid, Sasha and Hella, undated (Box 12)
    - Harkness, Rebekah West, no year August 2 (Box 12)
    - Harvill, Richard A., 1960-1972 (Box 12)
    - Hasterlick, Therese, 1966, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Hauser, Marianne, 1963-1973; 2 (Box 13)
    - Hawkins, Erick, 1965-1972 (Box 13)
    - Hayakawa, S. I. (Samuel Ichiyé) and Marge, 1969-1972 (Box 13)
    - Hershey, Phares R., 1964-1965 (Box 13)
    - Highlander Research and Education Center (Knoxville, Tenn), 1964-1965 (Box 13)
    - Hillery, Mable A., 1965-1968 (Box 13)
    - Holmes, Dolores and Carl, 1969-1971 (Box 13)
    - Holmes, Phoebe Barton, 1961-1969; 3 (Box 13)
    - Holmes, Phoebe Barton (continued), 1961-1969; 2 (Box 14)
    - Hyland, Thomas, 1962-1971 (Box 14)
    - "I" general, 1962-1972 (Box 14)
    - India - miscellaneous, 1963-1966 (Box 14)
    - "J" general, 1962-1972; 2 (Box 14)
    - Jacob, Bernard and Devon Meade, 1966-1972 (Box 14)
    - Jamaica, B.W.I. (British West Indies), [1946] (Box 14)
    - Janus, Christopher G., 1961-1963 (Box 14)
    - Jasinski, Marianna, 1970-1973 (Box 14)
    - Jha, Lansman, 1963-1972 (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Ben, 1968-1969 (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Marjorie, 1968-1970; 3 (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Vilas, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
    - Jones, Sheridan, 1962-1966 (Box 15)
    - Josephson, Hannah and Matthew, 1965-1972 (Box 15)
    - Julian, Betty and Bill, 1961-1971 (Box 15)
    - "K" general, 1961-1972; 2 (Box 15)
    - Kam, Leilani, 1965-1973 (Box 15)
    - Kanaseki, Hisao and Kuniko, 1966-1972 (Box 15)
    - Kapur, Jagdish, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Kiesler, Frederick, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, 1966-1973 (Box 15)
    - King, Terry and Tom, 1965-1973 (Box 15)
    - Kittinger, Hubert, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
    - Klinefelter, Margaret A., 1971-1973 (Box 16)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1939-1974; 2 (Box 16)
    - Alfred A. Knopf Inc., 1955-1964 (Box 16)
    - Kobori, Nanrei Sohaku
      - Correspondence, 1962-1974; 5 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence with The Record Hunter, 1972 (Box 16)
      - Ryoko-in - temple, 1964, 1972 (Box 16)
      - Ryoko-in - students, 1966-1972 (Box 16)
    - Kotelawala, John Lionel, Sir, 1961-1970 (Box 17)
    - Krauss Reprint Co., 1970 (Box 17)
    - Kumar, Ravi, 1964-1966 (Box 17)
    - Kutakov, L. N., 1969, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Kyotow, Kay (New York Travel Service), 1971-1973 (Box 17)
    - "L" general, 1960-1973; 2 (Box 17)
    - Lakhanpal, P. L., 1970, 1972 (Box 17)
    - Lall, Betty and Arthur, 1967-1972 (Box 17)
    - Lang, Christopher, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Leach, Henry Goddard, 1956-1962 (Box 17)
    - Libert, Jack, 1970-1973 (Box 17)
    - Library of International Relations, 1940-1973; 2 (Box 17)
    - Library of International Relations (continued), 1940-1973; 4 (Box 18)
    - Librería Internacional del Perú, 1945-1947 (Box 18)
    - Lincoln School, 1965-1967 (Box 18)
    - Living Theatre (New York, N.Y.), 1960-1961 (Box 18)
    - Lohia, Ram Manohar, 1962-1965; 2 (Box 18)
    - Long, Worth, 1964, 1966 (Box 18)
    - Lorang, Charles, 1957-1960 (Box 18)
    - Lucas, Marie, 1969-1974 (Box 18)
    - Lye, Len, 1964-1972 (Box 18)
    - "M" general, 1952-1974; 2 (Box 19)
    - Magistretti, Bill and Cathie, 1960-1969, undated (Box 19)
    - Marchesi, Jehanne-Marie, 1957-1958 (Box 19)
    - Masonick, Dorothy, 1965-1966 (Box 19)
    - McAdams, Peg and George, 1963-1970 (Box 19)
    - McCormick, Ada P., 1961-1971 (Box 19)
    - McIntosh and Otis, Inc., 1953-1962 (Box 19)
    - McMahan, Ian, 1964-1966 (Box 19)
    - Meredith, William, 1970-1971 (Box 19)
    - Migdal, Lester C., 1970, 1972 (Box 19)
    - Mitra, Roma, 1966-1973 (Box 19)
    - Miyawaki, Aiko, 1969-1970, undated (Box 19)
    - Miyazawa, Klichi, 1967-1971 (Box 19)
    - Mobley, Ainslie, 1959-1972; 2 (Box 19)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1963-1973 (Box 20)
    - Muir, Laurence A., 1964-1972 (Box 20)
    - Mukherjee, Sarat K., 1964-1973 (Box 20)
    - Murahari, Gaure, 1966-1973 (Box 20)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1961-1974 (Box 20)
    - "N" general, 1958-1972; 2 (Box 20)
    - Neininger, Jean Purcell and Urban, 1963-1970; 2 (Box 20)
    - Newman, Annalee and Barnett, 1964-1970 (Box 20)
    - New York University, 1972 (Box 20)
    - Nickerson, Adams H., 1964-1973 (Box 20)
    - Nickerson, Adams H. (continued), 1964-1973 (Box 21)
    - Nims, John Frederick, 1956-1973 (Box 21)
    - Nishiwaki, Junzaburo, 1962-1973 (Box 21)
    - Nordenfalk, Carl, 1964-1966 (Box 21)
    - "O" general, 1962-1969 (Box 21)
    - Okada, Kenzo, 1970, 1972 (Box 21)
    - Oshita, Atsushi, 1964-1967 (Box 21)
    - "P" general, 1950-1974; 2 (Box 21)
    - P.E.N. American Center, 1968-1974 (Box 21)
    - Parsons, Betty, 1968-1972 (Box 21)
    - Paulson, Arvid, 1961-1972 (Box 21)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1956-1973 (Box 21)
    - Pitcher, Oliver W., 1964 (Box 21)
    - Petty, Vickie Hoover, 1959-1964 (Box 21)
    - Pilotte, R. A. (Rose-Anna), 1964, 1966 (Box 21)
    - Poetry Magazine, 1937-1961; 2 (Box 22)
    - Poetry - miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1965 (Box 22)
    - Poetry - clippings, 1938-1961 (Box 22)
    - Pratt, S. J. (Leslie Ann), 1965 January 29, undated (Box 22)
    - Praz, Mario, 1961-1971 (Box 22)
    - "Q" general, 1973 March 26 (Box 22)
    - "R" general, 1957-1974; 2 (Box 22)
    - Race relations: correspondence and articles, 1964, 1970 (Box 22)
    - Rago, Henry, 1962 (Box 22)
    - ReQua, Eloise G., 1960-1973 (Box 22)
    - ReQua, Eloise G. (continued), 1960-1973; 3 (Box 23)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1961-1973; 2 (Box 23)
    - Reynolds, Paul R., 1966-1969 (Box 23)
    - Richardson, Lois and David, 1966-1967, undated (Box 23)
    - Roberts, Margaret Cucci, 1953-1973 (Box 23)
    - Roberts, Warren, 1969, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Robinson, Virginia Morgan, 1963-1969 (Box 23)
    - "S" general, 1952-1974 (Box 23)
    - "S" general (continued), 1952-1974; 3 (Box 24)
    - Sahlin, Nils G. (Nils Gösta), 1961-1973 (Box 24)
    - Sakakida, Kishio, 1965-1971 (Box 24)
    - Sam Harper Memorial, 1943-1946 (Box 24)
    - Sandoz, Mari, 1962-1972 (Box 24)
    - Sasaki, Ruth Fuller, 1960-1969; 2 (Box 24)
    - Schary, Saul and Hope, 1965, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Schelling, Elinor (Paula), 1966-1972 (Box 24)
    - Scott, Franklin, 1965-1972 (Box 24)
    - Seacombe, James, 1969-1973 (Box 24)
    - Senanayake, W. D., 1963-1970 (Box 24)
    - Shelton, Richard, 1963-1973; 2 (Box 25)
    - Shirer, William L. (William Lawrence), 1965-1973 (Box 25)
    - Simmonds, Harvey, 1965-1972 (Box 25)
    - Simon, Edwin, 1971-1973 (Box 25)
    - Skalski, André, 1963-1964; 2 (Box 25)
    - Smith, Frances, 1963-1964 (Box 25)
    - Snyder, Gary, 1963-1965 (Box 25)
    - Spater, Hope and George, 1966-1974 (Box 25)
    - Stadler, Albert, 1964-1970 (Box 25)
    - Steloff, Frances, 1965-1966 (Box 25)
    - Stephan, Frederick W., 1947-1961; 5 (Box 25)
    - Stephan, Frederick W. (continued), 1947-1961; 5 (Box 26)
    - Stephan, John J.
      - Correspondence, 1962-1973; 2 (Box 26)
    - Stephan, John (Box 26)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 26)
      - Painting exhibits, 1950-1960 (Box 26)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1965; 2 (Box 26)
      - Memorial fund, 1966-1968 (Box 27)
    - Still, Clyfford, 1951-1969; 2 (Box 27)
    - Strauss, Harold, 1951-1971; 2 (Box 27)
    - "T" general, 1958-1973; 2 (Box 27)
    - Talman, E. Lee, 1958-1964 (Box 27)
    - Tanck, Olivia H., 1969-1973; 2 (Box 27)
    - Taylor, Lucy, 1964-1968 (Box 27)
    - Tegen, Gunhild, 1961-1969 (Box 28)
    - The Texas Quarterly, 1973 (Box 28)
    - The Tiger's Eye
      - Correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 28)
      - Kraus Reprint, 1966-1974; 2 (Box 28)
    - Toda, Yasushi, 1965-1973 (Box 28)
    - Tree, Marietta, 1965, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Turbeville, Gus, 1959-1973 (Box 28)
    - Turner, John, 1963-1964 (Box 28)
    - "U" general, 1960-1971 (Box 28)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1958-1970 (Box 28)
    - United States Government, 1966-1968; 3 (Box 28)
    - University of Arizona. Poetry Center
      - Board Meeting minutes, 1969-1974; 6 (Box 29)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1974; 9 (Box 29)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1960-1974; 3 (Box 30)
      - Clippings, etc., 1963-1965 (Box 30)
      - Comments, 1973 July (Box 30)
      - Expenses, 1959-1972; 2 (Box 30)
      - Original book list, 1960-1973 (Box 30)
      - Photographs and brochures, 1965-1974; 2 (Box 30)
      - 10th anniversary celebration, undated (Box 31)
      - Year end reports, 1962-1972 (Box 31)
    - University of Arizona Press, 1971-1973 (Box 31)
    - University of Bridgeport - Van Wyck Brooks Awards, 1968-1970 (Box 31)
    - University of Chicago, 1935-1955 (Box 31)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1965 (Box 31)
    - University of Texas Press, 1961-1965 (Box 31)
    - University of Texas - Ruth Stephan Poetry Center, 1965-1973; 2 (Box 31)
    - "V" general, 1962-1971 (Box 31)
    - Vallancey, Dick, 1963-1965 (Box 31)
    - Vannicelli, Maria, 1964-1974 (Box 31)
    - Vietnam - correspondence and articles, 1968 (Box 31)
    - Von Eckermann, Ebba and Erik, 1966-1973 (Box 32)
    - "W" general, 1961-1974; 2 (Box 32)
    - Walgreen, Chuck, 1951-1974; 6 (Box 32)
    - Walgreen, Myrtle R. Norton, 1959-1972; 2 (Box 32)
    - Walgreen family correspondence, 1959-1971; 5 (Box 33)
    - Wardlaw, Frank, 1957-1971; 2 (Box 33)
    - Washington Square Village, 1964-1969 (Box 33)
    - Weerasinghe, O. (Oliver) and Christobel, 1962-1969 (Box 33)
    - Westphalen, Emilio Adolfo, 1955-1974 (Box 33)
    - Wickremesinghe, Esmond, 1963-1970 (Box 33)
    - Wilder, Isabel and Thornton, 1960-1964 (Box 33)
    - Wilkins, Sophie, 1964, 1966 (Box 33)
    - Williams, Owen, 1965-1973 (Box 33)
    - Wilson, Carroll L., 1969-1973 (Box 34)
    - Wilson, Keith, 1964-1971 (Box 34)
    - Wise, Edward N., 1965-1969 (Box 34)
    - Wrigley, Helen and Phil, 1961-1973 (Box 34)
    - "X-Y-Z" general, 1961-1973 (Box 34)
    - Yale University Library, 1960-1972 (Box 34)
    - Young, Marguerite, 1951-1969; 4 (Box 34)
    - Zadkine, Ossip, 1963-1965 (Box 34)
    - Zen Center - California, 1966-1969 (Box 34)
    - Zeri, Federico, 1958-1972 (Box 34)
    - Zierold, Norman, 1964-1965 (Box 34)
  - Subject Files
    - Adopted children (Box 35)
    - Art in Dixon (Box 35)
    - Book list, 2 (Box 35)
    - Book restoration (Mr. Halpin) (Box 35)
    - Books in storage, 1951 (Box 35)
    - Books, stationery, subscription (Box 35)
    - Children's book list, 1958 (Box 35)
    - Childhood letters, 1915-1928; 3 (Box 35)
    - Childhood letters (continued), 1915-1928; 5 (Box 36)